<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Leonard</title>
    <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Leonard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh_Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 13:13:29 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wzdlc1996.github.io/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth Audio Issues</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/linux/bluetoothaudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 13:13:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/linux/bluetoothaudio/</guid>
      <description> Switch HSV to A2DP A2DP not working with PulseAudio Here is the explanation from ArchWiki: A2DP not working with PulseAudio
With Blueman-manager version 2.06 and PulseAudio version 12.2 , there is an issue that one cannot switch to A2DP with GUI. It will post the error message that Fail to change profile to A2DP . It seems only happening in Gnome. One need to avoid the GDM to start PulseAudio. The solution is:
 Edit /etc/pulse/default.pa to close the default Bluetooth discover of pulse.
nano /etc/pulse/default.pa # load-module module-bluetooth-discover  Edit /usr/bin/start-pulseaudio-x11 to open bluetooth discover by pactl . It should be:
nano /usr/bin/start-pulseaudio-x11 if ... if [ x”$SESSION_MANAGER” != x ] ; then /usr/bin/pactl load-module module-x11-xsmp “display=$DISPLAY session_manager=$SESSION_MANAGER” &amp;gt; /dev/null fi #Insert this line# /usr/bin/pactl load-module module-bluetooth-discover fi  Usually this block of code is at the last line.
  This solution is from:
 Linux &amp;amp; Bluetooth BBS. Arch at #17 ArchWiki.Chinese Simplified  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual Graphic Card Configuration for Manjaro Linux</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/linux/nvidiasetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 14:48:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/linux/nvidiasetting/</guid>
      <description>Introduction usually, linux has two method to handle the dual-graphic card. The difference between them are:
   Method Advantages Disadvantages     Bumblebee Uses dGPU(descrete) only when requested. Saving power Manjaro default Some overhead so lower raw performance   PRIME Uses the dGPU directly , Better performance dGPU and iGPU(integrated) both powered on constantly need manual configuration    Step 1. Remove Bumblebee Usually manjaro can be easily installed choosing the free drive mode, but nouveau is hard to use. And sometimes it make user cannot entry the x-system. One way is that noting nouveau in blacklist , use command:
sudo nano /etc/modprob.d/usrBlack.blacklist blacklist nouveau  Then to use the graphic card, one can run mhwd-tui to install the non-free driver and Bumblebee to manage dual graphic card. First of all, we need uninstall bumblebee, and may the graphic card driver installed by mhwd. One can simply remove them using the mhwd command in terminal or via Manjaro Settings Manager In other distribution, the work is the same. User can using their package manager to do it. Or more directly, do NOT install bumblebee, directly install PRIME after truning off nouveau.
Step 2. Install Closed-source Driver One can follow the following articles to install the driver according to what he use:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>