<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews on Leonard</title>
    <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/categories/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews on Leonard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh_Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wzdlc1996.github.io/categories/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>对一般刚体的定点转动的统计力学分析</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/elementary/rigidbodystat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/elementary/rigidbodystat/</guid>
      <description>在统计力学中, 我们通常会关注正则动量与坐标. 因为由它们确定的相空间体积元在正则变换下不变. 但在我们实际进行计算时, 却并非总是正则动量与坐标的表达最为方便. 一个例子就是刚体力学中, 我们会偏爱使用转动惯量和惯量主轴的方法来讨论问题. 然而作为角动量, 它们彼此之间并不对易, 因而在处理统计力学积分时往往带来困惑: 我们能使用它们作为被积变量吗? 进一步的, 用刚体转动模型理解多原子分子热容时同样会遇到这个问题. 本文旨在对这个问题给出解答: 在讨论不依赖转动构型的力学量时, 使用主轴角动量作为动力学变量是完全可行的. 变量替换的 Jacobian 只是转动构型的函数.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Measurement Based Quantum Computing</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/measbasedqcomputing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 22:16:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/measbasedqcomputing/</guid>
      <description>In this note, we will generally discuss the basic conceptions of measurement-based quantum computing(MBQC). We focus on the workflow of MBQC and how to transpile a circuit-based model to MBQC. The parallization for quantum computing and other optimizations are not fully covered but the references are offered. Finally, we discuss the development of MBQC in theoretical perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in Quantum Mechanics, Up to 2021</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/mlinqphy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 22:50:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/mlinqphy/</guid>
      <description>In the recent(at 2021) decades, machine learning algorithms have been popular in almost all disciplines of science and even art. People have found out that a huge share of research and production problems can be viewed as instances of basic tasks that could get well solved with the modern powerful hardware and algorithms. In physics, there has been already plenty of applications covering data manipulation and model/theory discovering. However, just like those famous algorithms in the past, machine learning has its own caveats. Researchers should get well understanding about the boundary of algorithms&amp;rsquo; ability. Being a well-trained user instead of package importer would be the new requirements of people in related fields. In this review, we will discuss the success applications of machine learning in quantum physics in recent years and the potential limitation. Then the reader could get a clearer picture on the development of machine learning and quantum physics frontier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time in Quantum Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/timeinqm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 18:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/timeinqm/</guid>
      <description>Time in quantum mechanics is always left as an parameter in the equation of motion. In the non-relativistic quantum theory we find time in the derivative of wavefunction, while in the relativistic quantum field theory, it is not at the same status of spatial position: we introduce the space-time dependent field operator only for Lorentz covariance for the equation of motion. Whether can we have an intrinsic interpretation of time flow in quantum mechanics was early discussed by Don Page and William Wootters with the purpose to match the energy superselection rule. Though it may not be a correct theory for our world or even &amp;lsquo;close&amp;rsquo; to it, it is worthy to discuss in modern view here as a consistent approach to the time puzzle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Methods for Schrodinger Equation</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/numschrodinger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 22:50:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/numschrodinger/</guid>
      <description>The first problem we meet in the practice about quantum mechanics is to simulate the quantum time evolution on computer. Formally, it is the numerical simulation of the (time-dependent) Schrodinger Equation. In this review, we discuss various numerical method for the Schrodinger equation and quantum time evolution, including their implementation and error analysis. We will only focus on the non-relativistic quantum mechanics, i.e., the number of degree of freedom is finite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Machine Learning: Quantum Algorithms to Classical Data</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/qmachinelearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 14:16:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/qmachinelearning/</guid>
      <description>Quantum machine learning is the integration of quantum algorithms within machine learning programs. Generally, we have four different approaches for this purpose, by the type of data (quantum state/data or classical data) and type of algorithm or platform (quantum algorithm/computer or classical algorithm/computer). In this report, we focus on an elementary discussion about aspect of the quantum approach to classical data. The more attractive part about quantum approach to quantum data will be left for future posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Travel and Quantum Computation</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/ctcquantcomputing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 15:54:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/ctcquantcomputing/</guid>
      <description>Time travel, as a famous concept in science fiction, fascinates people for a long time. However for physicists, this is not only a beautiful dream, but also a interesting problem to discuss mathematically. In the community, there are generally two directions about time travel: (1) does it exist and (2) if it indeed exists, what can we do. In this report, we discuss the application of time travel mainly in the field of quantum computation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Weak Measurements and Weak Values</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/weakmeasurement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 16:10:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/weakmeasurement/</guid>
      <description>An introduction to weak measurement and weak values. Using the simplest model and perturbation theory to analyze a class of weak measurement process and the concept of weak values. This article gives a comparison between weak measurement and the ordinary measurement in quantum mechanics(which is called as strong measurement) and some interesting application of weak values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Zeno Effect</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/zenoeffect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 19:23:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/artic/physics/zenoeffect/</guid>
      <description>The quantum Zeno effect: an unstable particle will never be found to decay if it is continuously observed. The theoretical analysis and the experiment. And a simple introduction for Many worlds interpretation</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
