<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Field-Theory on Leonard</title>
    <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/series/field-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Field-Theory on Leonard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh_Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 14:14:27 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wzdlc1996.github.io/series/field-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interacting Field Theory: Scattering Theory</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/intftii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 14:14:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/intftii/</guid>
      <description>We will review the scattering theory which has been studied in quantum-mechanics. The main character is the S-matrix and how to compute cross section by it. Then we will introduce the Lehmann-Symanzik-Zimmermann reduction fomula, which will show the connection between time-ordered Green&amp;rsquo;s function and S-matrix in scattering theory. The former can be computed by the Feynman Diagram and Feynman Rule which we have studied in the last section, and the latter is the only thing we can measure in experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interacting Field Theory: Time-ordered Green&#39;s Function</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/intfti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 15:42:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/intfti/</guid>
      <description>We will introduce the basic Field Theory with interaction considered, which is the main propose of Field Theory actually. We will use the perturbation theory here. And what can we talk is only perturbation-property of Field theory. Our goal is to show the constraint of the form of Lagrangian in Interacting Field Theory. Then we will show the perturbation expansion of the time-ordered Green&amp;rsquo;s function and the corresponding method: Feynman Diagram and Feynman Rules. Green&amp;rsquo;s Function is widely used in field theory, especially in condensed matter theory. But in QFT we just care the connection between it and scattering theory, which will be discussed in next section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantization of Free Field: Maxwell Field</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/qtzfieldiii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 20:11:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/qtzfieldiii/</guid>
      <description>The canonical quantization of vector Field(Maxwell Field). One can find that the usual quantization procedure(directly using of commutation relationship) does not work for it, because of the Gauge Symmetry. We will introduce the Gupta-Bleuler quantization procedure. It clearly keeps the Lorentz covariance but leads to a Hilbert space with negative matric. For free Maxwell field we can separate them totally, so the probability interpretation will not destroyed. Then we will computation of propagator and do some discussion. At last we will discuss the discrete symmetry of Maxwell Field in Quantum Theory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantization of Free Field: Dirac Field</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/qtzfieldii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 16:27:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/qtzfieldii/</guid>
      <description>The canonical quantization of Spinor Field(Dirac Field). One can find that the usual quantization procedure(canonical commutation relationship) does not work for it, because it leads to the Hamiltonian with no lower bound. To quantize it correctly, we need modify it as the anti-commutation relationship, which means that Dirac particles are Fermions. Then we will computation of propagator and do some discussion. At last we will discuss the discrete symmetry of Dirac Field in Quantum Theory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantization of Free Field: Scalar Field</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/qtzfieldi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 14:29:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/qtzfieldi/</guid>
      <description>The canonical quantization of Real-valued Scalar Field(Klein Gordon Field). And computation of propagator and discussion, especially the causality property. At last we will discuss the discrete symmetry of Klein Gordon Field in Quantum Theory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classical Fields: Maxwell Field</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/classicalfieldsiii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 15:21:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/classicalfieldsiii/</guid>
      <description>The classical field theory for vector field, so-called Maxwell Field. Together with the solution of Maxwell equation and some properties of Maxwell field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classical Fields: Dirac Field</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/classicalfieldsii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 15:21:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/classicalfieldsii/</guid>
      <description>The classical field theory for Dirac spinor field, so-called Dirac Field. Together with the solution of Dirac equation and some properties of Dirac field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classical Fields: Scalar Field</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/classicalfieldsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 21:49:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/classicalfieldsi/</guid>
      <description>The classical field theory for scalar field, so-called Klein-Gordon Field. Together with the solution of Klein-Gordon equation and some symmetry analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classical Field Theory</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/classicalft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 15:20:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/classicalft/</guid>
      <description>The classical field theory. Lagrange &amp;amp; Hamilton Formalism and the Noether Theorem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Mathematics</title>
      <link>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/premath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 15:45:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wzdlc1996.github.io/notes/fieldtheory/premath/</guid>
      <description>The preliminary Mathematical knowledge for Quantum Field Theory. Containing the Minkowski Spacetime, Lorentz Group, and the representation theory of Lorentz Group.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>